

SHANU SIBBAL

Assistant Manager Restaurant

PROFILE

Highly efficient and customeroriented Food & Beverage Executive with 9 years of experience in food and hospitality environments. Adept communicator with team leading and development skills. Forward thinking multi-tasker able to analyse situations and costs and successfully determine profitable outcomes.

CONTACT

shanusibbal@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/shanusibbal521b2566

P - (+91) 7018392725

16 CD Adarsh Nagar, Alambagh

Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh

EXPERIENCE

CHICA, NEW DELHI

NOVEMBER 2021

Assistant Manager Restaurant

- Started working as an Assistant Manager Restaurant for Chica an upcoming Mediterranean, European, Asian cuisine-based outlet of 280 covers seating.
- Interviewed and Recruited team members for Preopening team.
- Planning, Organising and establishing inventory of tools and equipment.
- Prepared restaurant policies and procedures for providing customer focused service standards.

SIX SENSES FORT BARWARA, RAJASTHAN

AUGUST 2021- OCTOBER 2021

Executive Supervisor

- Was responsible for the entire Bar Operations.
- Oversaw the design, planning, building, staffing, creating menus, training.
- Worked under the guidance of Mr. Jonathan Heath, Corporate Director Food and Beverage.

THE LEELA PALACE HOTELS & RESORTS, BANGALORE

MARCH 2021 - JULY 2021

Executive Supervisor

- Managed the CGS Inventory
- Conducting Team briefings
- Handling guest complaints and providing solutions
- Coordinated with the kitchen staff for daily item availability
- Managed guest's special dietary needs
- Handled VVIP guests
- Overseeing purchasing to stay within certain budget
- Ensured all covid regulations are followed

THE OBEROI HOTELS AND RESORTS, SUKHVILLAS, CHANDIGARH

FEBRUARY 2017 – FEBRUARY 2021

SUPERVISOR

- Responsible for the opening of 'Kaanan' specialty restaurant
- Handled the par stock of Linen, crockeries, glassware, cutleries
- Managed staffing, leaves, appraisal etc.
- In charge of training
- Key responsibility in planning training schedules and executing them
- Achieved 1 cr against the forecasted revenue of 50 lakh YTD with 94% LQA
- Participated in the Executive Development Program 19-20
- Opportunity to work as a personal butler for renowned personality like Mr. Rashpal Todd, Swapan Seth, Abhimanyu Munjal etc.
- Achieved zero shortage continuously after taking charge of the bar and organized promotion of summer cocktails

ACTIVITIES AND INTERESTS

Music, Travelling, meeting new people, Reading about food and beverage

THE OBEROI WILDFLOWER HALL, SHIMLA

MARCH 2016 – JANUARY 2017 SENIOR FNB ASSISTANT

- Trained and supervised servers to dish out exceptional service in terms of time, quality and personalization
- Supervised the mise en place of all stations to ensure smooth functioning
- Checked and ensured serviceability of furniture and equipment
- Controlled the cutlery inventory and service equipment
- Assigned duties ensuring equity of work
- Inspected the layout to ensure they meet the set standards
- Successful completion of Supervisory Development program and scored 80%

THE OBEROI CECIL, SHIMLA

MAY 2013 – DECEMBER 2015

FNB SERVICE ASSISTANT

- Attended daily briefings prior to outlet opening equipped with the basic aids of operations
- Learned du jour, not available items, menu preparations and their presentation
- Completed mise place and mise en scene prior to restaurant opening
- Cleaned and polished allotted silverware, cutlery, glassware and chinaware
- Stocked the sideboards with sauces, jams, salt and pepper cruets, butter dish, linen and other service ware
- Daily requisition of fresh linen and flowers from housekeeping
- · Received, greeted and seated guests
- Upsell food and beverage

TRAINING

PRIDE PARK PREMIER, GURUGRAM

JULY 2011 – NOVEMBER 2011

VIVANTA BY TAJ, LUCKNOW

MAY 2012 – JUNE 12

EDUCATION

B. SC. HOTEL AND HOSPITALITY ADMINISTRATION

DESH BHAGAT INSTITUTE OF HOTEL MANAGEMENT, GOBINDGARH, PUNJAB 2010 – 2013

HIGHER SECONDARY CERTIFICATE

SPRING DALE SCHOOL, LUCKNOW, UTTAR PRADESH APRIL 2010

KEY SKILLS AND CHARACTERISTICS

- Quick learner
- Positive attitude
- Communication
- · Guest handling
- Multitasking
- Working under pressure
 - · Work for long hours
 - Neophile

ACCOLADES

- Awarded for the highest upselling of wines
- Several employee of the month awards
- Employee of the year 2018-2019
- Certified departmental training program OCLD
- Executive development program 2019-2020 OCLD

DECLARATION

I SHANU SIBBAL HERE BY DECLARE THAT THE INFORMATION GIVEN ABOVE IS TRUE TO THE BEST OF MY KNOWLEDGE.